Liyou Zhang

San Francisco, CA · <u>liyou713@gmail.com</u> · 747 242 9039 · <u>github.com/liyouzhang</u> · Authorized to work in the U.S.

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with three years of quantitative analytical experience in healthcare, logistics and financial industries. Recognized for fast learning ability and culture adaptability. Key qualifications:

- Machine Learning and Deep Learning with Python, Sklearn, Pandas, SQL, Spark, MongoDB, AWS
- Financial Modeling with advanced Excel in DCF modeling, M&A, Bloomberg; passed CFA level 1 exam

EXPERIENCE

Galvanize – Data Science Immersive

San Francisco, CA

Partnered with Kiva for capstone project; received Google sponsorship for education

08/2018

- <u>Capstone Project</u>: partnered with Kiva.org to build lender archetypes with unsupervised machine learning algorithms
- Other projects: natural language processing (<u>topic modeling</u>), supervised machine learning (<u>user churn prediction</u>), regression (<u>price prediction</u> of heavy machinery), backend and database building (<u>fraud detection</u>)

Roche / Genentech – Finance Perspectives

Basel, Switzerland / San Francisco, CA

Global Leadership Development Program (1 of 3 selected from 1000+)

01/2017-03/2018

- Managed the P&L of two product alliances with annual profit sharing expense at \$1.2B; responsibilities included monthly closing, settlement payment, financial forecasting & budgeting, and business planning across multiple teams
- Supported management committees on financial aspects of disputes, litigation and strategic decision making
- Analyzed Medical Activities cost structure and set up benchmarks for future budget planning and transparency
- Improved overall team efficiency including reducing redundant questions 90% through designing and implementing a new platform as first-level support for financial queries from business units

DP World - Investor Relations, M&A, Group Treasury Intern

Dubai, U.A.E.

Sponsored by Dubai Government (Dubai Business Associates Program, 1 of 40 selected from 4000+)

08/2015-08/2016

- Proactively identified 5 strategic acquisition assets through extensive M&A research covering 60 ports
- Delivered an industry ROCE benchmark presentation to the deputy CFO based on analysis of seven competitors
- Built a financial model and conducted an in-depth case study of a competitor to gain insights on South East Asia

Caisse de dépôt et placement du Québec (CDPQ) - Research Intern

Beijing, China

2nd largest Canadian sovereign fund

09/2014-12/2014

- Monitored private equity market and complied daily reports for the HQ investment decisions
- Drafted China Mission brochure to introduce investment themes including Healthcare, Entertainment industries

BNP Paribas – Fixed Income Sales Intern

Beijing, China

Specialized in FX products

11/2013-01/2014

- Provided direct corporate clients support on FX hedging solutions, including daily pricing, generating term-sheets etc.
- Updated pitch books and scenario analysis worksheets; translated 10+ research reports to serve clients in China

EDUCATION & LEADERSHIP

Renmin University of China - Master of Finance

Beijing, China

GPA: 3.90/4, First Class Scholarship

Sciences Po - Exchange Program

Paris, France

Renmin University of China – Bachelor of Economics

Beijing, China

Honored Graduates of Beijing City (3%), Co-Founder of Lean In RUC

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: Native in Mandarin, fluent in English